# Scot Itakura

scot.itakura@gmail.com | (909) 684-1552 Oakland, CA 94611 LinkedIn
https://www.linkedin.com/in/scot-itakura-289376157
Portfolio
https://scotitakuraportfolio.web.app
Github
https://github.com/scotitakura

## Summary

Front-end web developer with a background in scientific data analytics and scientific coding programs as an Earth Science graduate from UC Santa Cruz. Recently certified through UC Berkeley's Full-Stack Web Development program, employing my scientific program experience with MATLAB, Python, ArcGIS to become adept at web programs such as JavaScript, Node.js, React.js, etc. Successfully developed an interactive, responsive, and visually attractive web page for a business's primary customer hub as a freelance web developer. Striving to create visually superb and enjoyably interactive web pages that are unique, memorable, and dependable.

## **Technical Skills**

React, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js, Express, Styled Components, Materialize, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js Microsoft Excel, Python, SciPy, MATLAB, Geographic Information System (ArcGIS), STELLA

# **Projects**

# QualiTrees | https://github.com/scotitakura/QualiTreesWeb | https://qualitrees-503dd.web.app/

## Corporate Website

- Freelance solo project built with React for a start-up business to display products, information about the business, ways to contact, and frequently asked questions. Deployed with Firebase.
- Notable features include:
  - > Design that is aesthetic and complementary to the client's brand
  - > Infinite and forward animations
  - Mobile responsiveness

# Garage Collage | https://github.com/jennifermulder/garage-endeavor | https://garage-collage-2468.herokuapp.com/ *E-commerce Website*

- Held full responsibility for the front end of a three person group project. Built and created with React and styled using Styled Components, a fully functional garage sale e-commerce website was deployed with Heroku and completed within two weeks.
- Notable features include:
  - Complex and intriguing animations
  - > Seamless patterns used to create unique backgrounds
  - ➤ Mobile responsiveness

## **Work Experience**

# **Community Integration Assistant**

(Jan. 2020 - Present)

Ability Now Bay Area | Oakland, CA

Educate and empower adults with disabilities and their families through advocacy, wellness, and building independence over online classes from the safety of their homes.

#### **Staff Engineer**

(July 2019 - Nov. 2019)

Berlogar Stevens & Associates | Pleasanton, CA

Support Project Managers with tasks associated with subsurface exploration including laboratory testing, construction monitoring and testing services during mass grading, foundation preparation, pile installation, and tieback installation.

#### **Geotechnical Engineering Technician**

(Sept. 2018 – June 2019)

Cornerstone Earth Group Inc. | Sunnyvale, CA

• Conduct geotechnical site observations of earthwork, utility backfill, drainage improvements, excavations, and foundation construction.

#### Education

## **Full-Stack Web Development Certificate**

2020

University of California, Berkeley

## Earth Science, Bachelor of Science

(2014 - 2018)